Guide to the Juan Felipe Herrera Papers, ca. 1970-1998 M1043
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 13: Accession 2014-117
  - Kung Fu Jazz. T. Hernandez. Poems. Chapbook. Tiger Sign Productions. 12 pages. 1999. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Beyond This Body. Elaine Marcus Starkman. Sheer Press. 1987. Signed. 40 pages (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Semana de la Mujer. Chapbook. Chicana/Latina Writings. UC Riverside. 2004. 12 pages. And 2003 Issue. 11 pages. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - There is Right and There is Wrong. Margaret Randal. Red Trapeze Mono-Poem Magazine. Vol. 2. No. 1. SF. 1 Sheet. 1981. Yvonne Yarbro-Bejarano. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - From my Heart Revolution. George Tirado. Mass Extinction Press. SF. 1993. And the Assembly of God as Jasper. A.L. Nielsen. Backwoods Broadsides. Chaplet Series. #69. Signed. (see #70) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Picas. Robero Bedoya. Exempli Gratia press. Berkeley, Ca. 1986. 8pags. Notes by JFH. And Loma Prieta by Francisco X. Alarcon. We Press. 1990. Signed. 32 p-gs (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Typewriters are LeftHanded. Adrienne Renee Colombara. Student Thesis. Chapbook. 2007. 32 pgs. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Bone. Arlene Biala. Chapbook. 1993. Signed. Helmut Press. 28 pgs. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Taos Poetry Circus. 21st Anual Program Booklet. 32 pgs. 6-16-02 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - The Chicana Feminist. Martha Cotera. Information Systems Development. Austin, Texas. 1977. Signed. 66 pgs. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Campesino Fingerprints. Rod Ricardo-Livingstone. Calaca Press. San Diego, Ca. 2000. 32 pages. Chapbook Series #1. Signed. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Sharp Shooter. Tim Hernandez. Visalia, Ca. No te Aweetes Prod. 2/98. 24 pgs. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Semana de la Mujer. Chicano Student Programs. UC-Riverside. Poems. 2001. 14 pages. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - For Itzo. Truong Tran. Chapbook. (Itzolin Garcia - son of Garcia-Camarillo, poet. Died at a young age while attending Stanford.) 14 pgs. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Beside the Wichita. Lonnie Poco. March Press. Chicago. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Find me skinny. Mike Medrano. Fresno, Ca. 2000. 8 pgs. And Reinventing the Hard Bop. Double Chapbook with Tim Hernandez (Still Shot). A Brown Scat Production. 2/99 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - An Aztec Memory. Charles Fishman. The Anabiosis Press. 1996. 28 pages. Signed. (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - #40 Untitled (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Calif... (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Puro Pedo Magazine. Vol. 2. Issue 2. 2008 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Inlandia. Draft Concept for Inlandia Anthology to be published by Heyday publishers, Berkeley. (by JH students in creative writing class, 2007). (1 of 3) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Inlandia. Draft Concept for Inlandia Anthology to be published by Heyday publishers, Berkeley. (by JH students in creative writing class, 2007). (2 of 3) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Inlandia. Draft Concept for Inlandia Anthology to be published by Heyday publishers, Berkeley. (by JH students in creative writing class, 2007). (3 of 3) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Compost. A Journal of Art, Literature and Ideas. No. 8. Winter 1996-97. (Multicultural Issue). Jamaica, MA. 1997 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Revista Chicano-Riquena. Vol. XI No. 2. 1983 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - De Anza Faculty Edition. De Anza Community College. Cupertino, Ca. 1984 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Que Sigan Las Mariposas. Let the Butterflies Continue. A Poetry Reading By Soujourner Kincaid-Rolle - Una Lectura Para Armando Vallejo. 10/18/1992. UCSB Multicultural Center. 2/25/1993. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Xalman. Alma Chicana de Aztlan. Palabras del Pueblo. Santa Barbara. July, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Xalman. Spring, 1979. Vol. 2 No. 2. Santa Barbara. 1979 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Huellas. Edited by Xalman. Vol. 1. No. 5. Fall 1977 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Xalman. Corridos y Canciones de Aztlan. Vol. III. No. 2 Fall 1980. Santa Barbara, Ca. 1980 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Una Lectura de Poesia. Marcos Antonia Montes de Oca, Julio Ortega, Armando Vallejo. La Casa de la Raza, Santa Barbara, Ca. January 13, 1987 (Chapbook) (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Reflexiones Mezcladas. (Ed Armando Vallejo). 1/15/1981. Santa Barbara, Ca. 1981 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Copper Thunderbird. Pajarotrueno de Cobre. Armando Vallejo. La Casa de la Raza. Santa Barbara, Ca. 3/1987 (Chapbook) (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Reel Rasquache. Festival of the U.S. Latino Experience in Film and Art-2005. CSU-LA. 4/29-5/1. 2005. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - The El Monte Berry Strike of 1933. Ronald W. Lopez. Aztlan Publications (reprint). UCLA. Los Angeles, Ca. Undated. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Poemas de un Emigrante - Poems of an Immigrant. Armando Vallejo. Santa Barbara, Ca. 1990. (Chapbooks) (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Blank Furs. Being an Anthology of Poems by the Summer Arts Poets. CSU-Summer Arts. Alan Soldofsky, Coord. 1989 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Heirs. Vol. 9. San Francisco, Ca. 1973 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Aztlan. Chicano Journal of the Social Sciences and the Arts. Fall. 1970. Vol. 1. No. 2. UCLA. Los Angeles. 1971 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - 7th Annual Bisbee Poetry Festival. Bisbee, Az. (Rochelle Owens, Ed Sanders, Kathy Acker, Jane Cortez, JFHerrera, John Ashbury. 1985 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Maize. Xicano Art and Literature Notebooks. Vol1. No. 5. Primavera. San Diego, Ca. 1978. (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Para morir en tus brazos y compromiso, Poesia Chicana 1973-1988, Santa Barbara. Ediciones Xalman. 1989. (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Untitled Oxygen. No. 17. San Francisco, Ca. 1997 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - La Voz Poetica del Chicano. El Grito Quarterly Book Series. Year VII. Book 3. March-May 1974 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - El Grito. A Journal of Contemporary Mexican American Thought. Vol.II No.4. Summer 1969 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - El Grito. A Journal of Contemporary Mexican American Thought. Vol.III. No. 2. Winter 1970 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - El Grito. A Journal of Contemporary Mexican American Thought. Vol. I. No. 2. Winter 1968 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - El Grito. A Journal of Contemporary Mexican American Thought. Vol. V. No. 3. Spring 1972 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Maize. Cuaderno de Arte y Literature Xicana. Vol. 1. No. 2. San Diego, Ca. 1977 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Maize. Cuaderno de Arte y Literature Xicana. Vol. 1. No. 3. San Diego, Ca. 1978 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Maize. Cuaderno de Arte y Literature Xicana. Vol. 4. No. 1-2. Fall-Winter 1980-81. San Diego, Ca. 1981 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Maize. Cuaderno de Arte y Literature Xicana. Vol. 5. No. 1-2. San Diego, Ca. 1982 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Maize. Cuaderno de Arte y Literature Xicana. Vol. 5. No. 3-4. San Diego, Ca. Spring - Summer 1982 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Maize. Cuaderno de Arte y Literature Xicana. Vol. 6. No. 3-4. San Diego, Ca. Spring-Summer 1983. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Contract II Vol. 6. No. 34-35. (Latino Issue) Bowling Green, NYC. 1985 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Lusitania #5. For Za Sarajevo. (with poem by JFH in Serbo-Coratian) Fall. New York. 1993 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Rio Grande Review. Fall 2008. Issue #2. UTEP. El Paso, Tx. 2008 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - CrossRoads. Contemporary Political Analysis and Left Dialogue. May 1993. No. 31. (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Electrum. A Quarterly Poetry Magazine. No. 38. Spring 1986 (with letter from Margaret Randall to JFH tucked inside - 12/7/1985) (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - High Performance. A Quarterly Magazine for the New Arts Audience. #35. Nuevo Latino. Vol. Nine. ).2. 1986 (with post card from Danny Moreno tucked inside, May, 1985) (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Llueva Tlaloc. Numero 10. Pima Community College. 1983 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Tierra Adentro. Instituto Nacional de Bellas Artes en la Provincia. Mexico #31-32. (with features on Poetasumanos [formed by JFHerrera in San Francisco] - with Francisco X. Alarcon, Tina Alvarez Robles, Yvonne Yarbro-Bejarano, JFH and Victor Martinez). 1983. (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Oxygen. (Numbers: 8,9,10,11 [with post card from editor - Richard Hack], 13, 15, 16). San Francisco. 1993-96. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Mango. Vol. 1. No. 3-4. With inner-chapbook by Pancho Aguila. And poems by major Chicano poets. Ed. Lorna Dee Cervantes. 1977. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - El Cocodrilo. Revista de Poesia. Ano 2. Numero 7/8. Otono-Invierno. 1994/1995. Mexico, DF. Mexico. 1995. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Diccionario de la Imaginacion. Poesia y Cuento. Taller Infantil de Creacion Literaria - Nacimiento. INBA, Mexico, DF. 1985 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Penola. Numero dos. Vol. 1. Guadalajara, Jalisco, Mexico. 1979 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Penola. Numero 4. Vol. 1. Guadalajara, Jalisco, Mexico. Enero-Mayo 1980 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Penola. Numero 5. Vol. 2. Guadalajara, Jalisco, Mexico. [with poetry by JFH] Marzo-Abril 1981 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Penola. Numero 6. Nueva Epoca. Guadalajara, Jalisco, Mexico. 1984 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - As de corazones rotos. Revista bimestral de Poesia. [with poem by JFH] Mexico, DF. Mayo-Junnio 1980 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Red Trapeze. Monopoem Magazine. Vol1. No. 3 (printed on Gestetner Machine at La Galeria de la Raza, 24th and Bryant, SF). "Suicide in Hollywood/Lupe Velez - Serigradia de una Actriz Mexicana (circa 1923)" by JFHerrera. March 1980 (this is a one page magazine that Poetasumanos initiated in my apartment - 949 Capp Street, SF.) (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Untitled Folder (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Untitled Folder (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Untitled Folder (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Untitled Folder (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Untitled Folder (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Habla Notebook Zendo / 60 sheets / 3-7-14 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Tao Moves Sketchbook/100 Sheets/ 5-9-10 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Scraper Zendo Boys/100 Sheets/ 5-9-10 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Con Cancion y letra Candela Sketchbook/ 100 Sheets/ 8-4-03 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Full Moon River Tao Sketchbook/ 100 Sheets/ 1/25/05 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Yellow Ferris Wheel poetry selection from unpublished ms. 10-22-04 (Ten poems - poems on pages 3,4,7,9,10,11 not published). (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Parrot in the Oven. Victor Martinez. Japanese Translation by Yumiko Sakura. 1998. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - The Adventure of Chiko Yonke in Puropartytime Town. Draft for children's musical for La Jolla Playhouse, La Jolla, Ca. 13 pages w/ two small sheets of notes. And two page outline. With letter from Director, Steve McCormick. This script led to the final work - Salsalandia. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Chapbook: The Spider Who Walked Underground. By Tony Moffeit. Kangaroo Court #4, Erie, PA. 1985 (poems on images of Hank Williams). Signed. Given to me in Bisbee, Az. 1985. 17 pgs. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Chapbook: Madrugada del '56. Selected Poems by Raymundo Gamboa. Lalo Press Publicatons La Jolla, Ca. 1978 (Ernesto Padilla Publisher and editor). 39. pgs. Signed. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Chapbook: Bad Boys. Sandra Cisneros. Mango Press. San Jose, Ca. Chicano Chapbook Series #8. 1980. 8 pgs. (Box 10, Folder 4)